sesamestreet.org 2000-05-06

# CTW - Privacy Policy

**Children's Television Workshop Online  
Privacy and Fair Information Practices Policy  
for CTW Family Workshop (ctw.org) 

Version 2.0 — April 20, 2000 

**

**Privacy Policy Summary**

We offer this summary to encourage parents to read and understand our Privacy Policy. For more details, click on the link at the end of each paragraph. 

**Children's Television Workshop has been trusted by parents for more than thirty years to provide safe, entertaining, and reliable products and content. We take this trust very seriously, especially as we expand our online presence. We recognize that families are concerned about privacy and especially about the privacy of their children online. CTW Family Workshop, its staff, contractors, and others who help us operate our Web site follow this policy on privacy and fair information practices for online activities of CTW Online. CTW Online always meets or exceeds the requirements of the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998.**

**1\. Trust, Notice and Security**

At CTW Family Workshop, we fully disclose our policy about the collection, maintenance, use, disclosure, and security of personal information obtained from users of our online activities. By personal information, we mean a name, address, email address, telephone number, or any other information that can be used to contact an individual. (more)

**2\. Parental Involvement and Consent**

Parental involvement in a child's CTW Family Workshop activities is a cornerstone of our approach to the Internet. CTW Family Workshop does not currently collect and maintain personal information from children. We will require prior parental consent should we ever collect and maintain personal information from children under the age of 13. (more)

**3\. Use and Disclosure Limitations**

CTW Family Workshop uses personal information about its Web site users only in defined and responsible ways. We do not share user information with third parties except when we have told users about the disclosures, when we have prior consent, or when required by law. When we do share information with sponsors, we allow users to opt-out of receiving any unsolicited email. (more)

**4\. Information Collection**

CTW Family Workshop fully explains its information collection practices. We do not collect personal information from children. We tell adults when information is required and when it is optional. (more)

**5\. Access to and Correction of Personal Information**

CTW Family Workshop is committed to maintaining accurate, timely, relevant, and appropriate information about our users. (more)

**6\. Complaints**

CTW Family Workshop pledges to work with users to resolve any complaints about our privacy and fair information practices policy or our implementation of the policy. (more)

**7\. Technical and Other Matters: Cookies, Web Logs, and Advertisers**

CTW Family Workshop discloses the defined and limited way that our Web site uses cookies, Web logs, and advertising. (more)

**Detailed Policy Description**

**1\. Trust, Notice, and Security**

**At CTW Family Workshop, we fully disclose our policy about the collection, maintenance, use, disclosure, and security of personal information obtained from users of our online activities. By personal information, we mean a name, address, email address, telephone number, or any other information that can be used to contact an individual.**

Concerns about privacy can be stronger in the online environment. CTW Family Workshop promises to follow this privacy and fair information practices policy that we specially designed for our Web site. Parents can trust CTW Family Workshop will not misuse any personal information about their children or about themselves. 

CTW Family Workshop will change over time as we add exciting new features, services, and options. The Internet itself will also change as new capabilities and perhaps new laws emerge. This policy will be updated occasionally. Our philosophy of protecting user information from inappropriate uses and disclosures will not change. We promise to provide appropriate advance notice through the Web site of any change that materially affects the collection, maintenance, use, or disclosure of personal information from children or adults. We will also seek parental consent should we ever decide to collect and maintain personal information from children. Other changes to this privacy policy statement that reflect refinements, improvements, updates, and new features will be made as appropriate and posted as soon as possible. Whenever the privacy policy changes, we will modify the date and version number to reflect that a change was made. 

Another important element of trust is security. The security of personal information is a high priority at CTW Family Workshop. We maintain this Web site and all associated data with technical, administrative, and physical safeguards to protect against loss, unauthorized access, destruction, misuse, modification, and improper disclosure. We follow industry-proven security procedures such as encrypted administrative communication, restricted access to underlying machines, and firewalls at network access points. No computer system or information can ever be fully protected against every possible hazard. CTW Family Workshop is committed to providing reasonable and appropriate security controls to protect our Web site and its information against foreseeable hazards. 

CTW Family Workshop requires that employees and contractors who have access to personal information from the Web site acknowledge in writing that they have read these privacy and fair information practices rules and that they are expected to follow it. 

This Web site is operated by CTW Family Workshop located at One Lincoln Plaza, New York, N.Y. 10023. Our telephone number is 212-595-3456. Our E-mail address is [privacy@ctwonline.com](mailto:privacy@ctwonline.com). 

**2\. Parental Involvement and Consent**

**Parental involvement in a child's CTW Family Workshop activities is a cornerstone of our approach to the Internet. CTW Family Workshop does not currently collect and maintain personal information from children. We will require prior parental consent should we ever collect and maintain personal information from children under the age of 13.**

CTW Family Workshop encourages parents and caregivers to spend time online with children and to collaborate in the learning and fun offered at our Web site. The Internet is a wonderful place to explore as a family. We recommend that an adult accompany children when using content on the Internet. 

Our Web site has been designed to delight children and adults alike. We offer parental education and online child safety programs for our audience. We encourage parents to take advantage of these programs to teach their children about online safety and to supervise their children online. 

CTW Family Workshop recognizes that collecting personal information from visitors to our Web site can be sensitive. Many features do not require disclosure of a name, E-mail address, or other personal information. Some features need personal information in order to work. We want our users to understand what information we collect and how we use it. We also want to provide our users with a choice when possible. 

**3\. Use and Disclosure Limitations**

**CTW Family Workshop uses personal information about its Web site users only in defined and responsible ways. We do not share user information with third parties except when we have told users about the disclosures, when we have prior consent, or when required by law. When we do share information with sponsors, we allow users to opt-out of receiving any unsolicited email.**

Use Policy: When CTW Family Workshop gathers personal information from users, we ask for permission first. We also disclose, at the time of collection, how the information will be used by us. Personal information is used for activities such as site registration, site membership, online sweepstakes that require notification of winners, newsletter subscriptions, and mailings that describe upcoming products, events, and features. 

User Choice: Whenever possible, CTW Family Workshop allows users to make choices about how their personal information will be used. For example, when you register for the Discussion Board, you are asked if you object to making your E-mail address available to other discussion members. Also, if we plan to use your information for CTW Family Workshop marketing or advertising purposes, we let you tell us in advance that you do not want to receive any mail about our activities or promotions or about offers from our sponsors or advertisers. For example, when you register for our newsletter, you are asked if you object to our using the information to contact you about new features and content on our Web site. 

Disclosure Policy: We do not normally disclose personal information to anyone outside of CTW Family Workshop unless we have previously informed users about the disclosures. However, some data may be used from time to time by outside auditors, consultants, and others hired by CTW Family Workshop to assist in carrying out financial or operational activities. We permit these uses only when necessary to manage the Web site and its records or for another specific purpose consistent with this privacy policy. All recipients must agree in writing to safeguard personal information, to use it only for an authorized purpose, and to return it or destroy it upon completion of the activity. 

CTW Family Workshop might be required to disclose personal information in response to valid legal process. This includes a search warrant, subpoena, or court order. In this respect, we are no different from any other record keeper. Disclosures may also be appropriate to protect the safety of a child, during emergencies if physical safety is believed to be at risk, to protect the security or integrity of our Web site, or to take precautions against liability. We think that these events are unlikely, but they are possible. We will take reasonable steps to limit the scope of any of these disclosures. 

**4\. Information Collection**

**CTW Family Workshop fully explains its information collection practices. We do not collect personal information from children. We tell adults when information is required and when it is optional.**

_**Information About Children**_

CTW Family Workshop does not collect personal information from children. 

One of our most popular offerings for children does not require personal information. It is Kid City, and its primary feature is Sticker World. In Sticker World, children provide a nickname and password to create their own Web page and to trade stickers with others. The nicknames and passwords are not connected to personal identifiers. Children using the site are effectively anonymous. 

Sweepstakes and Contests for Children: We sometimes offer children the opportunity to enter a sweepstakes or contest for a prize through Sticker World or other online activities. Children enter the sweepstakes or contest using screen names only. We do not collect any personal information from children entering sweepstakes and contests. 

Winners are notified through messages delivered to their mailbox on the CTW Family Workshop Web site. Winners under the age of 18 must then obtain parental approval, and parents must sign an Affidavit of Eligibility & Liability/Publicity Release. When necessary to deliver a prize, delivery information about the winner may be shared with a third party. 

Sesame Street Post Office: The Sesame Street Post Office allows a child or other person to receive an email response from a Muppet. A visitor to the Post Office selects a Muppet and asks a question from a fixed set of questions. The visitor provides only the first name and email address of the recipient of the reply. The Post Office is fully automated. It selects a prewritten answer to the question and emails the answer. No other emails will be sent to the visitor. 

_**Information About Adults**_

Member Center: CTW Family Workshop offers free membership for site visitors who are at least 18 years of age. Users who register through the Member Center can join discussion boards, enter sweepstakes, and receive newsletters. To be a Member of the CTW Family Workshop at the Member Center, a user must provide a member "name", password, first name, last name, E-mail address, gender, age, and zip code. Members may optionally provide other demographic information. Once registered, CTW Family Workshop Members may update their information at any time. 

The optional Member Center information is never revealed to anyone outside CTW Family Workshop. Some other information provided by the user may be shared with outside sponsors. If a sweepstakes has an outside sponsor, the E-mail addresses of those who enter the sweepstakes may be shared with the sponsor. Also, some information about subscribers to the Baby Workshop and the Crib Notes newsletter is shared with Baby Workshop sponsors. Details about opting-out of disclosures for sweepstakes and the Baby Workshop can be found later. 

Discussion Board: CTW Family Workshop operates a discussion area for parents to exchange ideas and advice. Discussion Board is for adults. Only Members of the CTW Family Workshop can participate, and Members must be age 18 or older. We believe that some of the best information comes from the families that participate on our Web site. These discussions are a valuable addition to the Web site and a great resource for our users. We will occasionally highlight posts from the discussions so that other users can more easily join a specific conversation and can quickly see how intelligent and helpful the Discussion Board can be. 

Discussions take place in a public arena. Post information only if you feel comfortable sharing it with others. To keep discussions safe and productive, trained professionals monitor and participate in the Discussion Board daily so that we can be sure that we are maintaining a quality environment. Our policy is to remove posts that include home addresses and telephone numbers. Please do not post this information in the Discussion Board. Only post your E-mail address or other contact information if you would like participants to contact you directly. 

The Discussion Board allows parents to post a user profile with any biographical information they care to include. All Discussion Board users are able to see these profiles. A parent who has posted a user profile can modify or deleted it at any time. User profiles are optional. 

Sweepstakes for Adults: We sometimes offer Members the opportunity to enter a sweepstakes for a prize, such as an Elmopalooza home video. Only Members of the CTW Family Workshop can participate, and Members must be age 18 or older. Winners are selected at random. They must provide an address so we can send the prize. If a sweepstakes has an outside sponsor, the E-mail addresses of those who entered may be shared with the sponsor. Sweepstakes entrants can opt-out of receiving any unsolicited email from a sponsor. When necessary to deliver a prize, delivery information about the winner of a sweepstakes may be shared with a third party. 

Newsletters for Parents: CTW Family Workshop offers weekly E-mail newsletters for parents. These include our CTW Family Newsletter and our Sesame Street Beat newsletter. Newsletter subscribers may receive occasional, unsolicited E-mail from CTW Family Workshop describing new online features and content or promotional offers. Subscribers can decline the opportunity to receive this E-mail when they register and can unsubscribe at any time. 

Baby Workshop: The Baby Workshop offers programming and information for new and expectant parents. Visitors become Members of the Baby Workshop by completing a registration form that requires user name, password, E-mail address, first name, last name, due date/age of child, and zip code. Members may optionally provide additional information about themselves and their family. Visitors may also become Members by signing up for Baby Workshop's free monthly Crib Notes newsletter. Once registered, Members may update their information at any time. 

Baby Workshop and the Crib Notes Newsletter are made possible with support from outside sponsors. Registration information for Baby Workshop Members is shared with the sponsors who may use it in the aggregate to make decisions about how to meet the needs of the members. Sponsors may also use email addresses to send occasional, unsolicited E-mail containing promotional announcements. Members can decline the opportunity to receive this E-mail when they join. Sponsors maintain information in accordance with their own privacy policies. Baby Workshop Members may also receive occasional, unsolicited E-mail describing new Workshop online features, content, or promotional offers. Members can separately decline the opportunity to receive this E-mail when they register. Members can also unsubscribe to the Crib Notes Newsletter at any time. 

Parents' Advisory Board: CTW Family Workshop operates a wholly voluntary Parents' Advisory Board that any CTW Family Workshop Member can join. Members of the Parents' Advisory Board are occasionally asked questions via E-mail about upcoming features we are considering. Input and opinions from users help us build a better site for you and your family. Responses to these questions from Members of the Advisory Board are used only to compile aggregate statistical information about Board Members. Once the answers are analyzed, any link between the answers and personal information is broken forever. 

**5\. Access to and Correction of Personal Information**

**CTW Family Workshop is committed to maintaining accurate, timely, relevant, and appropriate information about our users.**

CTW Family Workshop's commitment to data quality includes the recognition that we bear responsibility for maintaining accurate, timely, relevant, and appropriate information about our users. We cannot serve users properly with inaccurate data. 

We also recognize that we need the assistance of users to make sure that their information is correct because users are the source of the information. Users may review, correct, and update the information that we maintain about them. Users can review their information at the Member Center. For example, if you have provided a Member Profile, you can change it. You can also unregister for our newsletters. 

If you remove or change information on our system, the information may be retained for a period in our backup systems. Backup systems protect against the possibility of failures in the computer system. It can take weeks or months before information cycles out of backup systems. Information about purchases made through the CTW Web site may be retained for longer periods as required by law, contract, or auditing requirements. 

**6\. Complaints**

**CTW Family Workshop pledges to work with users to resolve any complaints about our privacy and fair information practices policy or our implementation of the policy.**

If you have a complaint about our privacy and fair information practices policy or about our implementation of the policy, you can write to us at [privacy@ctwonline.com](mailto:privacy@ctwonline.com). CTW Family Workshop will try to resolve any problems that arise in a fair and prompt manner. 

**7\. Technical and Other Matters: Cookies, Web Logs, and Advertisers**

**CTW Family Workshop discloses the defined and limited way that our Web site uses cookies, Web logs, and advertising.**

Cookies: On the Internet, a cookie is a piece of information that a Web site transfers to a user's computer for record-keeping purposes. As a user moves from page to page at our Web site, a cookie is the only way that we have of knowing who you are. An activity on one page may depend on what you selected on a previous page. We use a cookie to keep track of your selection. Without cookies, users may be asked to provide the same information repeatedly. Some activities may not function at all. 

The use of cookies is common on the Internet. Most major Web sites use cookies. CTW Family Workshop uses cookies only when appropriate. We never use cookies to retrieve information from your computer that was not originally sent in a cookie from us. We never use information transferred through cookies for marketing purposes. We never share cookies information with any third parties for marketing or other purposes 

You can control cookies from your end through Internet browsers (like Netscape and Explorer) or using other software. Most browsers are initially set to accept cookies. If you prefer, you can set your browser to alert you when cookies are in use. You may also disable or refuse cookies. You can also erase a cookie that has been placed on your computer by us or by others. If you do not allow cookies to be used in the traditional way, it is possible that some parts of the Web site, like the Discussion Board, will not function as we designed them. It is your choice. 

Web Logs: CTW Family Workshop maintains standard Web logs that record basic information about visitors to our Web site. These logs contain: 

  * The Internet domain from which you access CTW (e.g., AOL.com, ABC.edu) and the address of the Web site you linked here from. 
  * Your IP address. An IP address is automatically assigned when you log onto the Internet. Static IP addresses may be identifiable in some instances. Dynamic addresses are usually not identifiable. 
  * The type of browser (e.g., Internet Explorer or Netscape) and operating system (e.g., Windows 98) you use. 
  * The date and time you visited CTW, and the pages you saw. 

We use Web log information to design our Web site, identify popular features, and in similar ways. We do not try to identify individuals from Web logs or to link Web logs to other user information. However, if someone tries to damage our Web site or use it in an unauthorized or illegal way, we may share Web log information with law enforcement agencies. 

Advertising: Ads on the CTW Family Workshop (e.g., interactive banners) may allow a user to click through to a Web site maintained by an advertiser. CTW Family Workshop makes reasonable efforts to ensure that only advertisements suitable for children will appear on our Web site. Advertiser Web sites are not controlled by CTW Family Workshop. Advertisers may have different privacy policies, which we encourage you to review. When you click through to advertisers' Web sites, you may get cookies directly from them. CTW Family Workshop does not see or use these cookies, and we do not control how other sites use cookies. 

If a CTW Family Workshop advertiser wants to send you E-mail and if you have not objected to receiving promotions, we send the E-mail message on behalf of the advertiser. We do not disclose your information to the advertiser. If you leave our Web site by responding directly to an advertiser and then provide personal information, then the advertiser may use that information in accordance with its own policy. CTW Family Workshop only does business with responsible companies, but we cannot control the way that someone else uses information that you disclose directly to them. 

If you think that any sponsors, advertisers, or links on our Web site are inappropriate, please contact our CTW Family Workshop Neighborhood Watch program by E-mailing us at [watch@ctwonline.com](mailto:watch@ctwonline.com). 

DoubleClick: Some advertising on the CTW Family Workshop Web site is sold through DoubleClick, an independent Internet advertising company. We never disclose any individually identifiable information to DoubleClick. DoubleClick uses cookies to track Internet activities of users who have ever clicked on its advertising. You can opt-out of being tracked by DoubleClick. To opt-out, go to the DoubleClick site.
